<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Institute for Cultural Practices, University of Manchester on Chiara Zuanni</title>
    <link>http://example.org/institutions/institute-for-cultural-practices-university-of-manchester/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Institute for Cultural Practices, University of Manchester on Chiara Zuanni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/institutions/institute-for-cultural-practices-university-of-manchester/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Campus Obscurus</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_campusobscura-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_campusobscura-/</guid>
      <description>The project, part of a larger research programme by the PIs, focused on the development of a social media-based treasure hunt around the University of Manchester campus and Manchester cultural institutions, to engage students. My tasks included the preparation of the event (maps; hints; dissemination of QR codes and material for the &amp;ldquo;hunt&amp;rdquo;), supporting it (monitoring relevant social media channels and hashtags), and contributing to data collection for its evaluation and reporting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture Metrics</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2015_culturemetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2015_culturemetrics/</guid>
      <description>I contributed to the project by conducting literature reviews (on metrics in the cultural sector and in higher education), support in organising and delivering a workshop, social media data research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CultureFM</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_culturefm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_culturefm/</guid>
      <description>CultureFM explored different ways of using and interacting over Twitter, researching how these different ways of communicatoin could enhance digital engagement with arts organisations. As a research assistant, I did a review of existing Twitter analysis tools and methods; I supported the events (dissemination and technical support during the streams); and I contributed to collect and analyse data about the engagement generated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database of British auction catalogues of Chinese objects</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_summerpalace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_summerpalace/</guid>
      <description>I prepared a database and tables transcribing catalogues of British auctions, in support of Dr Tythacott&amp;rsquo;s research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mynightmuseum participatory digital game</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2013_nightmuseum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2013_nightmuseum/</guid>
      <description>mynightmuseum was a social media (mainly Twitter) event during Museums at Night. My role included supporting the Twitter event, and collecting and analysising the Twitter data afterwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Engagement with the Museum of Medicine and Health</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2016_manchmedicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2016_manchmedicine/</guid>
      <description>Preparation of a social media campaign across platforms; analytics; and contribution to an event at Manchester Histories Festival.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
