<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Projects on Chiara Zuanni</title>
    <link>http://example.org/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research Projects on Chiara Zuanni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Liverpool 2018: Legacies of the European Capital of Culture 10 Years On</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/postdoctoral-research-assistant/2016_liverpool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/postdoctoral-research-assistant/2016_liverpool/</guid>
      <description>The project &amp;ldquo;Impacts18&amp;rdquo; aimed to observe the long-term impact of the European Capital of Culture award on the city of Liverpool. In my role, I conducted press and social media data analysis; archival analysis in the City of Liverpool, and contributed to the preparation of interviews with key stakeholders, to the organisation of workshops, and to presentations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shakespeare Lives - Monitoring &amp; Evaluation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/postdoctoral-research-assistant/2016_shakespeare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/postdoctoral-research-assistant/2016_shakespeare/</guid>
      <description>I contributed to the writing of the funding application, and to the design and delivery of the research. I conducted press analysis (in English and Russian; and trained Chinese students in content analysis for Chinese news items) and contributed to social media analysis and to the preparation of interviews with key stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Histories and Universal Museums</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/postdoctoral-research-assistant/2017_uhum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/postdoctoral-research-assistant/2017_uhum/</guid>
      <description>The project aimed to develop a comparative critique of approaches to universal histories in museums and of the role of museums in building knowledge about the future. I was the postdoctoral researcher on the project and I was therefore responsible of archival research (in London and Paris), co-organisation of the four workshops, development of the project website and its digital exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</guid>
      <description>tasks and short description
slug: &amp;lsquo;/2018_AncIt&amp;rsquo; title: &amp;lsquo;Getty Institute in Ancient Itineraries (2018-2019)&amp;rsquo; shortTitle: &amp;lsquo;Ancient Itineraries&amp;rsquo; date: &amp;ldquo;2018-06-01&amp;rdquo; tags: [&amp;ldquo;semantic web&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo;] statuses: [&amp;ldquo;completedLead&amp;rdquo;] Getty Institute in Ancient Itineraries (2018-2019) Role: Member PIs: Dr Stuart Dunn (KCL), Prof Graeme Earl (KCL), Dr Arianna Ciula (KCL), Dr Will Wootton (KCL); Dr Anna Foka (University of Uppsala) Funding: Getty Foundation Description: The project sought to investigate the potential and impact of &amp;lsquo;digital&amp;rsquo;, and in particular linked open data, on art history research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</guid>
      <description>tasks and short description
slug: &amp;lsquo;/CuratingBornDigital&amp;rsquo; title: &amp;lsquo;Curating Digital Data in Museums - workshop (2019)&amp;rsquo; shortTitle: &amp;lsquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; tags: [&amp;ldquo;contemporary collecting&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo;] statuses: [&amp;ldquo;completedLead&amp;rdquo;] date: &amp;ldquo;2019-02-02&amp;rdquo; Curating Digital Data in Museums - workshop (2019) Role: PI Funding: ca. € 4000 (Faculty of Humanities, University of Graz) Description: A workshop with international speakers on the topic of born-digital collections in museums. The event examined new curating practices emerging in response to the collecting and archiving of born-digital data; responses to the coexistence of physical and digital heritage in museum collections and displays; methodological issues raised by the acquisition of born-digital (big) data (including current research on collection management systems and metadata for this content); ethical and legal questions concerning the use of this data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</guid>
      <description>tasks and short description
slug: &amp;lsquo;/other&amp;rsquo; title: &amp;lsquo;INTERREG Danubes Archaeological eLandscapes&amp;rsquo; tags: [&amp;ldquo;semantic web&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo;] statuses: [&amp;ldquo;ongoing&amp;rdquo;] date: &amp;ldquo;2019-01-01&amp;rdquo; Contributor (UniGraz being associate member) to the EU INTERREG Danubes Archaeological eLandscapes (2020-2023, led by Universalmuseum Joanneum Archaeology): contributing to social archaeology strand, with a focus on digital public archaeology. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</guid>
      <description>tasks and short description
slug: &amp;lsquo;/DariahTheme&amp;rsquo; title: &amp;lsquo;Contemporary collecting and COVID-19: barriers, bottlenecks, and perspectives in digital curation (2020-2021 - DARIAH Theme)&amp;rsquo; shortTitle: &amp;lsquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; tags: [&amp;ldquo;COVID-19&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;contemporary collecting&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo;] statuses: [&amp;ldquo;ongoing&amp;rdquo;] date: &amp;ldquo;2020-11-11&amp;rdquo; Contemporary collecting and COVID-19: barriers, bottlenecks, and perspectives in digital curation (2020-2021 - DARIAH Theme) Role: PI Funding: € 8670,00 Description: The project aims to survey collections of memories and witnesses of the pandemic, identifying the processes and challenges encountered by memory organisations in dealing with such contemporary and (often) born-digital material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</guid>
      <description>tasks and short description
slug: &amp;lsquo;/DigiCulture&amp;rsquo; title: &amp;lsquo;DigitalCulture. Improving the Digital Competences and Social Inclusion of Adults in Creative Industries (2018-2021 - Erasmus+)&amp;rsquo; tags: [&amp;ldquo;skills&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo;] statuses: [&amp;ldquo;completedLead&amp;rdquo;] date: &amp;ldquo;2018-01-10&amp;rdquo; DigitalCulture. Improving the Digital Competences and Social Inclusion of Adults in Creative Industries (2018-2021 - Erasmus+) Role: Local PI. Partners: Polytechnic of Timisoara (coordinator - Romania), University of Roma Tre (Italy), University of Aalborg (Denmark), Dublin City University (Ireland), Fundaţia Interart TRIADE (Romania), JME Associates Ltd (UK), National Association of Distance Education (Lithuania).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</guid>
      <description>tasks and short description
slug: &amp;lsquo;/Gipsmuseum&amp;rsquo; title: &amp;lsquo;Virtual Gipsmuseum (work-package within DiTAH)&amp;rsquo; tags: [&amp;ldquo;semantic web&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo;] statuses: [&amp;ldquo;ongoing&amp;rdquo;] date: &amp;ldquo;2020-09-09&amp;rdquo; Virtual Gipsmuseum (work-package within DiTAH) Role: co-I of this workpackage (2020-2021), within the flagship project DiTAH led by Prof Georg Vogeler (BMBWF funding, 2020-2024) Partners for the work-package: Dr Elisabeth Trinkl - Institute of Archaeology, University of Graz Funding: ca. € 26.000,00 Description: The project is using LiDAR scans and photogrammetry to create a virtual museum of the cast collection (Gipsmuseum) of the department of archaeology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</guid>
      <description>tasks and short description
slug: &amp;lsquo;/Habil&amp;rsquo; title: &amp;lsquo;Habilitation&amp;rsquo; tags: [&amp;ldquo;contemporary collecting&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;audience research&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo;] statuses: [&amp;ldquo;ongoing&amp;rdquo;] date: &amp;ldquo;2018-01-05&amp;rdquo; Habilitation I am writing my Habilitation (a requirement for tenure in the Austrian system) on data practices in museums, with a focus on social media data and contemporary collecting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</guid>
      <description>tasks and short description
slug: &amp;lsquo;/HFDTeducation&amp;rsquo; title: &amp;lsquo;Museum Digital Materials and Online Learning during the Pandemic​ (2020-2021 - HFDT funding)&amp;rsquo; tags: [&amp;ldquo;skills&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;COVID-19&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;audience research&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo;] statuses: [&amp;ldquo;completedLead&amp;rdquo;] date: &amp;ldquo;2020-10-10&amp;rdquo; Museum Digital Materials and Online Learning during the Pandemic​ (2020-2021 - HFDT funding) Role: co-I Partners: Prof Kathrin Otrel-Cass (Institute of Education Research and Teacher Education, University of Graz) Funding: € 9816,00 Description: This small project aims to research the use of museum digital material in school programmes during the COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</guid>
      <description>tasks and short description
slug: &amp;lsquo;/MuseumsCovid&amp;rsquo; title: &amp;lsquo;Map of museum digital initiatives during the COVID-19 pandemic&amp;rsquo; tags: [&amp;ldquo;COVID-19&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo;] statuses: [&amp;ldquo;ongoing&amp;rdquo;] date: &amp;ldquo;2020-06-06&amp;rdquo; Map of museum digital initiatives during the COVID-19 pandemic (not funded) I developed a map aiming to collect and present the range of digital projects promoted and launched by museums since March 2020.
Project assistant: Sabrina Melcher Link: https://digitalmuseums.at </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</guid>
      <description>tasks and short description
slug: &amp;lsquo;/ReInHerit&amp;rsquo; title: &amp;lsquo;Redefining the Future of Culture Heritage, through a disruptive model of sustainability (2021-2024 - H2020)&amp;rsquo; tags: [&amp;ldquo;skills&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo;] statuses: [&amp;ldquo;ongoing&amp;rdquo;] date: &amp;ldquo;2021-03-03&amp;rdquo; Redefining the Future of Culture Heritage, through a disruptive model of sustainability (2021-2024 - H2020) Role: Local PI and WP leader. Partners: Bank of Cyprus Cultural Foundation (coordinator - Cyprus), Museum of Cycladic Art (Greece), CYENS Centre of Excellence (Cyprus), UNIC - School of Law (Cyprus), materahub (Italy), Arte Sostenible (Spain), Media Integration and Communication Center - University of Florence (Italy), Graz Museum (Austria), ECTN - European Cultural Tourism Network (Belgium), Arcada - University of Applied Sciences (Finland), Hellenic Committee of the Blue Shield (Greece).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/senior-researcher/-filename-/</guid>
      <description>tasks and short description
slug: &amp;lsquo;/seadda&amp;rsquo; title: &amp;lsquo;COST Action SEADDA&amp;rsquo; tags: [&amp;ldquo;semantic web&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo;] statuses: [&amp;ldquo;completedLead&amp;rdquo;] date: &amp;ldquo;2019-01-01&amp;rdquo; Substitute member in Management Committee for the COST Action SEADDA (2019-2023) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campus Obscurus</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_campusobscura-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_campusobscura-/</guid>
      <description>The project, part of a larger research programme by the PIs, focused on the development of a social media-based treasure hunt around the University of Manchester campus and Manchester cultural institutions, to engage students. My tasks included the preparation of the event (maps; hints; dissemination of QR codes and material for the &amp;ldquo;hunt&amp;rdquo;), supporting it (monitoring relevant social media channels and hashtags), and contributing to data collection for its evaluation and reporting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture Metrics</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2015_culturemetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2015_culturemetrics/</guid>
      <description>I contributed to the project by conducting literature reviews (on metrics in the cultural sector and in higher education), support in organising and delivering a workshop, social media data research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CultureFM</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_culturefm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_culturefm/</guid>
      <description>CultureFM explored different ways of using and interacting over Twitter, researching how these different ways of communicatoin could enhance digital engagement with arts organisations. As a research assistant, I did a review of existing Twitter analysis tools and methods; I supported the events (dissemination and technical support during the streams); and I contributed to collect and analyse data about the engagement generated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database of British auction catalogues of Chinese objects</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_summerpalace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2012_summerpalace/</guid>
      <description>I prepared a database and tables transcribing catalogues of British auctions, in support of Dr Tythacott&amp;rsquo;s research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exhibition &#34;Scripting the Globe. Italian Literary Journals in the World. 1945-1962&#34;</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2014_mancitalian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2014_mancitalian/</guid>
      <description>Co-curator of this temporary exhibition at the International Anthony Burgess Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mynightmuseum participatory digital game</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2013_nightmuseum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2013_nightmuseum/</guid>
      <description>mynightmuseum was a social media (mainly Twitter) event during Museums at Night. My role included supporting the Twitter event, and collecting and analysising the Twitter data afterwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Engagement with the Museum of Medicine and Health</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2016_manchmedicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2016_manchmedicine/</guid>
      <description>Preparation of a social media campaign across platforms; analytics; and contribution to an event at Manchester Histories Festival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Strategy and Analytics work</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2014_socialmediaanalytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/doctoral-research-assistant/2014_socialmediaanalytics/</guid>
      <description>I have supported the Kipling Society in developing a social media strategy; and I have developed social media analytics and evaluation reports for the Manchester Histories Festival and the School of Arts, Languages, and Cultures (University of Manchester). Besides, I have managed social media for a range of project and event accounts, as well as for some student engagement campaigns at the Institute for Cultural Practices (University of Manchester).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
